Guide to the Richard Maass Collection of Westchester and New York State 1645-1995, (Bulk: 1645-1910) MSS 055
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III: Mayors and Governors Autographs
  - Subseries A: Letters and Documents
    - creator: Van Cortlandt, Jacobus. place: New York, Dec 12, 1710; 055-003-A-1923; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 18)
      Legal document relating to the inability of several witnesses to appear for a defendant because they must go to sea. Signed by Van Cortlandt.
    - creator: Hunter, Robert, 1666-1734. place: Albany, Oct 10, 1711; 055-003-A-1924; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 19)
      physical description: fragment, silked; d. s.
      dimensions: 21cm x 19cm
      Official notification by Hunter to the Lord High Treasurer of Great Britain that he has allocated payment to several individuals for the building of two forts and chapels. Signed by Hunter.
    - creator: Clarke, George, 1676-1760. place: New York, Apr 22, 1712; 055-003-A-1925; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 20)
      An order to Clarke by William Matthews to pay twenty pounds to Robert Drummond. Signed by Clarke.
    - creator: Hunter, Robert, 1666-1734. place: New York, Dec 20, 1712; 055-003-A-1926; 2.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 21)
      dimensions: 38cm x 30cm
      Docketed: Account of the estate of William Fowler. Acknowledgment of receipt signed by Hunter.
    - creator: Heathcote, Caleb. place: New York, Dec 20, 1713; 055-003-A-1929; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 22)
      dimensions: 21cm x 21cm
      Docketed: Deposition of Albertus Bosch. Signed by Heathcote.
    - creator: Johnston, John. place: New York, Sep 27, 1715; 055-003-A-1930; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 23)
      physical description: half sheet, partially printed, mounted on cardboard.; d. s.
      Naturalization of Daniel Bonnet.
    - creator: Jansen, Johannes. place: New York, Oct 5, 1715; 055-003-A-1931; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 24)
      Deposition of dispute over maritime wages. Signed by Jansen.
    - creator: Hunter, Robert, 1666-1734. place: [New York], Jan 16, 1717; 055-003-A-1932; 6.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 25)
      physical description: six separate half sheets; d. s.
      Docketed: Ordinance establishing ferry rates for several routes.
    - creator: Schuyler, Peter. place: New York, Sep 25, 1719; 055-003-A-1919; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 26)
      Records the oath of administrator of the estate of Arch. Blake sworn before Schuyler. Signed by Schuyler.
    - creator: De Peyster, Abraham, d.1768? place: New York, Jun 21, 1720; 055-003-A-1940; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 27)
      physical description: fragment; a. d. s.
      Receipt for money received from James Alexander. Signed by De Peyster.
    - creator: Burnet, William, 1688-1729. place: New York, Nov 22, 1720; 055-003-A-1941; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 28)
      Lewis Morris sworn in as junior clerk of the circuit court. Signed by Burnet.
    - creator: Provoost, David. place: New York, Oct 6, 1722; 055-003-A-1942; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 29)
      physical description: half sheet; a. d. s.
      An account of the duties collected on the importation of slaves. Signed by Provoost.
    - creator: Walter, Robert. place: New York, Apr 25, 1724; 055-003-A-1943; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 30)
      physical description: half sheet mounted in paper frame; d. s.
      Walter signs as mayor as a witness for a legal document.
    - creator: Burnet, William, 1688-1729. place: New York, May 7, 1724; 055-003-A-1944; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 31)
      Petition of Ann Holmes for letters of adminstration for the estate of her late husband. Petition granted and signed by Burnet.
    - creator: Burnet, William, 1688-1729. place: New York, May 27, 1724; 055-003-A-1945; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 32)
      dimensions: 23cm x 16cm
      Docketed: Elizabeth Kniffen is granted administration of her late husband's estate. Signed by Burnet.
    - creator: Montgomerie, John. place: New York, Dec 2, 1728; 055-003-A-1946; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 33)
      dimensions: 24cm x 13cm
      Docketed: Bills of exchange for 300 pounds sterling to be paid to David Barclay. Signed by Montgomerie.
    - creator: Morris, Lewis, 1671-1746. place: [New York], Jan 9, 1729; 055-003-A-1947; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 34)
      physical description: parchment, folded with wax seals.; d. s.
      dimensions: 54cm x 21cm
      Indenture of land in the North Ward of New York City. Signed by Morris and several individuals. Original item moved to Oversize 7/23/2004 by Mike Kelly, see Series IIIB Box 1 Folder, but a transcription is available in 34A.
    - creator: Lurting, Robert. place: New York, Oct 10, 1729; 055-003-A-1948; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 35)
      Docketed: Affadavit that the defendant (Thomas Warren) has absconded. Signed by Lurting and John Blake.
    - creator: Cosby, William, ca. 1690-1736. place: Fort George, Sep 24, 1733; 055-003-A-1949; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 36)
      physical description: full sheet folded, partially printed; d. s.
      dimensions: 29cm x 20cm
      Marriage certificate between John Springer and Elizabeth Bozworth. Signed by Cosby and his secretary.
    - creator: Cruger, John, d. 1744. place: New York, Apr 10, 1744; 055-003-A-1950; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 37)
      Docketed: Precept for the general sessions of the peace, May 1744. Signed by Cruger, Stephanus Van Cortlandt, and others.
    - creator: Holland, Edward. place: New York, Nov 14, 1747; 055-003-A-1951; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 38)
      physical description: fragment mounted in paper frame; d. s.
      dimensions: 11cm x 16cm
      Imposition of tax on a bill. Signed by Holland.
    - creator: Clinton, George, ca. 1686-1761. place: New York, Nov 23, 1747; 055-003-A-1952; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 39)
      physical description: half sheet, partially printed with wax seal.; d. s.
      dimensions: 32cm x 20cm
      Appointment of William Hogan to be captain. Signed by Clinton and John Catherwood.
    - creator: Clinton, George, ca. 1686-1761. place: New York, Apr 5, 1750; 055-003-A-1953; 2.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 40)
      dimensions: 38cm x 32cm
      License to Thomas Lane and Jordis Remsen to purchase Indian lands. Signed by Clinton and Goldsborough Banyar.
    - creator: Holland, Edward. place: New York, Jul 14, 1752; 055-003-A-1956; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 41)
      Docketed: Precept for August sessions. Proclamation signed by Holland and several aldermen.
    - creator: De Lancey, James, 1686-1761. place: New York, Aug 15, 1755; 055-003-A-1957; 2.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 42)
      To Spencer Phips.
    - creator: Cruger, John, 1710-1791. place: New York, Nov 2, 1759; 055-003-A-1960; 1.0 pages (Box 10, Folder 43)
      Docketed: Examination of John Lee. Signed by Cruger, Philip Livingston, John Bogert, Jr., Leonard Lipensard, and Peter Mesier.
    - creator: Hicks, Whitehead. place: [Seacaucus], Mar 20, 1765; 055-003-A-1961; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 44)
      Receipt of payment from William Bayard. Signed by Hicks.
    - creator: Moore, Henry, Sir, 1713-1769. place: Fort George, Mar 22, 1769; 055-003-A-1962; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 45)
      physical description: full sheet, folded and mounted on paper frame.; d. s.
      Order from Moore to Alexander Colden to survey and lay out ten thousand acres of land purchased on behalf of Colonel Staats Long Morris and others.
    - creator: Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809. place: Fort George, May 31, 1771; 055-003-A-1965; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 46)
      physical description: half sheet with paper seal; l. s.
      Order to Alexander Colden to lay out and survey 5,000 acres of land for Edward Smith and his associates. Signed by George Banyar and Dunmore.
    - creator: Tryon, William, 1729-1788. place: New York, Feb 8, 1772; 055-003-A-1968; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 47)
      Draft for payment to Andrew Elliot. Docketed by Nathaniel Coffin.
    - creator: Mathews, David. place: New York, Mar 3, 1777; 055-003-A-1971; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 48)
      physical description: half sheet, badly damaged; d. s.
      Deposition of John Stevens sworn before Mathews, regarding the activities of Garret Vanriper, a 'rebel,' recently released from jail.
    - creator: Tryon, William, 1729-1788. place: Fort George, Mar 8, 1777; 055-003-A-1974; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 49)
      physical description: full sheet, folded with wax seal. Partially printed.; d. s.
      dimensions: 32cm x 40cm
      Appointment of Hendrick Suydam as First Lieutenant in Kings County Troop of Horse.
    - creator: Tryon, William, 1729-1788. place: New York, Apr 2, 1778; 055-003-A-1975; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 50)
      physical description: half sheet folded with wax seal; d. s.
      Permit for John Lewis to take possession of confiscated property.
    - creator: Monckton, Robert, 1726-1782. place: Portsmouth, Nov 12, 1778; 055-003-A-1976; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 51)
      physical description: fragment; a. l. s.
      dimensions: 20cm x 24cm
      Requests special favors to be given to Major General de Verdrière.
    - creator: Tryon, William, 1729-1788. place: Kings Bridge, Jan 20, 1779; 055-003-A-1977; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 52)
      To Justice Clowes, Queens County. Requisition of forage for British army horses.
    - creator: Hardy, Charles, Sir, 1716?-1780. place: On board Victory, Jul 27, 1779; 055-003-A-1980; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 53)
      physical description: full sheet folded; a. l. s.
      To the Right Honourable Lord Viscount Shuldham. Docketed by Admiral Shuldman.
    - creator: Duane, James, 1733-1797. place: New York, Mar 3, 1780; 055-003-A-1981; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 54)
      dimensions: 20cm x 12cm
      Payment for translation of Dutch records. Docketed by Isaac Rysdyk, the translator.
    - creator: Mathews, David. place: [New York], Sep 3, 1781; 055-003-A-1982; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 55)
      physical description: half sheet folded; l. s.
      To William Walton, Magistrate of Police.
    - creator: Willett, Marinus, 1740-1830. place: Albany, Jan 15, 1782; 055-003-A-1983; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 56)
      To Henry Glen. Docketed: Wheat to be paid. Written on the back of certificate signed by Major John Throop.
    - creator: Clinton, George, 1739-1812. place: Poughkeepsie, Sep 2, 1782; 055-003-A-1986; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 57)
      dimensions: 34cm x 21cm
      To Gerard Bancker.
    - creator: Mathews, David. place: [New York], Apr 24, 1783; 055-003-A-1987; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 58)
      physical description: fragment partially printed; d. s.
      Permit for Connecticut man to reside 7 days in New York.
    - creator: Willett, Marinus, 1740-1830. place: New York, Jan 26, 1785; 055-003-A-1988; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 59)
      Receipt for payment. Signed by Willett.
    - creator: Clinton, George, 1739-1812. place: New York, May 11, 1786; 055-003-A-1989; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 60)
      physical description: full sheet folded; l. s.
      To the Delegates for the State of New York in Congress. Docketed: Governor Clinton's letter to the delegates regarding impost laws and passing a requistion.
    - creator: Clinton, George, 1739-1812. place: New York, Jun 23, 1786; 055-003-A-1990; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 61)
      physical description: full sheet folded, partially printed.; d. s.
      dimensions: 31cm x 40cm
      Appointment of Andrew Sydam as captain. Signed by Robert Harpur, Secretary, docketed by Capt. A. Snydam.
    - creator: Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809. place: Fort Charlotte, 1789; 055-003-A-1991; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 62)
      physical description: fragment mounted on cardboard; d. s.
      Authorization of payment to laborers who worked on the construction of a fortification on Barnett Hill, New Providence between July 1, 1789 and September 30, 1789.
    - creator: Radcliff, Jacob, 1764-1844. place: Albany, Feb 22, 1810; 055-003-A-1992; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 63)
      dimensions: 18cm x 24cm
      To S. M. Hopkins
    - creator: Radcliff, Jacob, 1764-1844. place: New York, Aug 25, 1817; 055-003-A-1993; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 64)
      physical description: partially printed, wove paper; d. s.
      dimensions: 17cm x 11cm
      Payment to R. Stephens. Signed by Radcliff and Bleecker.
    - creator: Clinton, De Witt, 1769-1828. place: [New York], Dec 20, 1817; 055-003-A-1994; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 65)
      physical description: mounted in paper frame.; a. l. s.
      To President James Monroe.
    - creator: Allen, Stephen, 1767-1852. place: [New York], Jun 16, 1821; 055-003-A-1995; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 66)
      physical description: partially printed, wove paper.; d. s.
      Examination of a female slave prior to manumission.
    - creator: Paulding, William. place: New York, Jul 2, 1827; 055-003-A-1996; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 67)
      physical description: partially printed; d. s.
      Check to J. Bailey. Signed by Paulding.
    - creator: Lee, Gideon, 1778-1841. place: [New York], Apr 26, 1828; 055-003-A-1999; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 68)
      To George Newbold. Records Lee's $10.00 for Greek relief fund.
    - creator: Livingston, Edward, 1795 or 6-1843. place: [New York], May 21, 1829; 055-003-A-2000; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 69)
      dimensions: 20cm x 10cm
      Bank draft in the amount of $100.00 signed by Livingston.
    - creator: Bowne, Walter, 1770-1846. place: New York, Oct 20, 1832; 055-003-A-2001; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 70)
      Check for $836.49 made out to the Estate of Mary McCrea, signed by Bowne, dated October 20, 1832.
    - creator: Bowne, Walter, 1770-1846. place: New York, undated; 055-003-A-2004; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 70)
      physical description: partially printed, mounted in paper frame; d. s.
      License for Robert Waite, Jr. to sell lottery tickets.
    - creator: Lee, Gideon, 1778-1841. place: New York, Jan 27, 1834; 055-003-A-2006; 4.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 71)
      physical description: full sheet folded, hole; d. s.
      Thomas Bell's sworn statement authenticating goods sold at auction, witnessed by Lee.
    - creator: Lee, Gideon, 1778-1841. place: New York, Sep 2, 1833; 055-003-A-2005; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 71)
      Check for $150.00 for Patrick Quirk, signed by Lee, dated September 2, 1833.
    - creator: Lee, Gideon, 1778-1841. place: New York, Sep 28, 1834; 055-003-A-2011; 3.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 72)
      To Rev. Timothy M. Cooley. Also includes address leaf and postmark.
    - creator: Lawrence, Cornelius W. place: New York, Oct 16, 1835; 055-003-A-2015; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 73)
      physical description: wove paper folded with wax fragments; a. l. s.
      dimensions: 41cm x 26cm
      To Samuel G. Bridgham, Mayor of Providence, RI.
    - creator: Harper, James. place: New York, Jul 26, 1844; 055-003-A-2016; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 74)
      physical description: partially printed, paper seal, backed with cloth; d. s.
      dimensions: 26cm x 38cm
      Passport for Samuel Stein.
    - creator: Kingsland, Ambrose. place: New York, Mar 1, 1852; 055-003-A-2017; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 75)
      dimensions: 35cm x 21cm
      Certificate of appointment as policeman for Edward B. Smith.
    - creator: Morris, Robert Hunter, 1802-1855. place: New York, Apr 29, 1853; 055-003-A-2018; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 76)
      physical description: blue wove paper; a. l. s.
      To G. C. Bronson. Recommendation for Eugene McGrath.
    - creator: Westervelt, Jacob. place: New York, May 1853; 055-003-A-2019; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 77)
      physical description: blue wove paper, folded; d. s.
      To Hon. G. C. Bronson. A recommendation for an appointment to the Custom House for Mr. Israel Miller. Signed by Westervelt and others.
    - creator: Wood, Fernando, 1812-1881. place: New York, Sep 22, 1856; 055-003-A-2022; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 78)
      physical description: wove paper, Mayor's Office letterhead; a. l. s.
      dimensions: 25cm x 20cm
      To Hon. G. F. (?) Fowler
    - creator: Wood, Fernando, 1812-1881. place: New York, Nov 9, 1859; 055-003-A-2023; 3.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 79)
      physical description: wove paper folded; a. l. s.
      dimensions: 27cm x 21cm
      To Hon. H. Alvise (?)
    - creator: Macy, R. H. place: New York, Mar 29, 1862; 055-003-A-2027; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 80)
      To Mr. H[enry] King.
    - creator: Macy, R. H. place: New York, May 23, 1863; 055-003-A-2030; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 81)
      To Henry King.
    - creator: Opdyke, George, 1805-1880. place: [New York], Jul 1, 1866; 055-003-A-2033; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 82)
      To Hon. Harry A. Singleton
    - creator: Hall, A. Oakey (Abraham Oakey), 1826-1898. place: New York, Aug 29, 1876; 055-003-A-2041; 3.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 83)
      physical description: wove paper folded, mounted on cardboard; a. l. s.
      dimensions: 26cm x 21cm
      To My dear [W.] Ripley.
    - creator: Hall, A. Oakey (Abraham Oakey), 1826-1898. place: New York, Jan 9/10, 1876; 055-003-A-2034; 3.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 83)
      To My dear Monford.
    - creator: Hall, A. Oakey (Abraham Oakey), 1826-1898. place: New York, undated, (Black Friday); 055-003-A-2038; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 83)
      dimensions: 23cm x 14cm
      To My dear Judy.
    - creator: Hewitt, Abram S. (Abram Stevens), 1822-1903. place: Burling Slip, Mar 2, 1881; 055-003-A-2045; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 84)
      To Hon. J. A. Bentley, Com. of Pensions, Washington.
    - creator: Gilroy, Thomas F. place: New York, Jan 18, 1893; 055-003-A-2048; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 84.5)
      physical description: wove paper, Office of the Mayor letterhead; t.l.s.
      To Hon. James H. Manning, Mayor, Albany, NY.
    - creator: Hewitt, Abram S. (Abram Stevens), 1822-1903. place: Burling Slip, Dec 18, 1897; 055-003-A-2051; 2.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 85)
      physical description: wove paper; t. l .s.
      dimensions: 20cm x 27cm
      To Major Wolfgang Goetz, M.D. The letter concerns the terms of sale for Hewitt's property at Greenwood Lake, for Goetz's establishment of a private sanitorium. The verso contains Goetz's handwritten reply, dated December 20, 1897, in which he states that the terms are too high, but proposes a trade for his residence on Saint Nicholas Avenue.
    - creator: Gaynor, William. place: Brooklyn, August 8, 1910; 055-003-A-2054; 1.0 pages (Box 11, Folder 86)
      physical description: mounted in paper frame; d.s.
      Check in the amount of $1.00. Signed by William J. Gaynor. The check is drawn on an account at the Kings County Trust Company and made out to the Brooklyn Club.
  - Subseries B: Oversize Materials
    Series III: Subseries B contains oversize material signed by various mayors or governors. It is housed in a flat box, with the exception of one item which is kept in the map case.
    - creator: Nicolls, Richard, 1624-1672. place: [New York], Aug 12, 1667; 055-003-B-2055; 2.0 pages (Box 12, Folder 1)
      physical description: two half sheets stitched together and sealed with wax; d. s.
      dimensions: 32cm x 42cm
      Confirmation of deed of two lots to Oloffe Stevens.
    - creator: Limerick, Thomas Dongan, Earl of, 1634-1715 place: New York, Aug 24, 1686; 055-003-B-2058; 1.0 pages (Box 12, Folder 2)
      physical description: portion of full sheet; d. s.
      dimensions: 36cm x 38cm
      License for Joseph Neson to purchase forty acres at Nantucket from the Indians.
    - creator: De Peyster, Abraham, d.1768?. place: New York, Jun 12, 1693; 055-003-A-1904; 1.0 pages (Box 12, Folder 2.5)
      Deed to a house sold by Jacobus Van Cortlandt to Anthony Lepinar. Signed by De Peyster as mayor, Van Cortlandt, witnessed by Rip Van Dam and Cornelius Jacobs.
    - creator: Morris, Lewis, 1671-1746. place: [New York], 1697; 055-003-B-2059; 1.0 pages (Box Map Case 2.K, Folder 3)
      physical description: Parchment; d. s.
      dimensions: ?cm x ?cm
      Establishes Morris's estate as the manor of Morrisania. Signed by Governor Fletcher, David Janison (?), with original seal.
    - creator: Morris, Lewis, 1671-1746. place: [New York], Jan 9, 1729; 055-003-A-1947; 1.0 pages (Box 12, Folder 3.5)
      Indenture of land in the North Ward of New York City. Signed by Morris and several individuals.
    - creator: Throop, E. J. place: Albany, Aug 11, 1832; 055-003-B-2060; 1.0 pages (Box 12, Folder 4)
      dimensions: 40cm x 25cm
      Commission for Donald McDonald as Major of the First Regiment of Light Infantry.
    - creator: Marcy, William L. (William Learned), 1786-1857. place: Albany, Jan 12, 1833; 055-003-B-2061; 1.0 pages (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Commission for Donald McDonald as Lieutenant Colonel of the First Regiment of Light Infantry.
    - Notes for Folders 1 and 2 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Other Historical Letters and Manuscripts
  Series IV contains documents which do not relate directly to the history of New York State. It contains only three items in one small legal box, but among these are included a Massachusetts resolution signed by Samuel Warren, Samuel Adams, and John Hancock, and an important letter from John Quincy Adams regarding the abolition of slavery.
  - creator: Conway, Thomas place: New Castle, Sep 28, 1778; 055-004-A-2062; 1.0 pages (Box 13, Folder 1)
    physical description: half sheet, stamped "Autograph Collection of Dr. Max Thorek Chicago"; a. d. s.
    In French. Conway recommends Captain DesEspiniers.
  - creator: Warren, Samuel place: [Boston], Jul 6, 1787; 055-004-A-2063; 1.0 pages (Box 13, Folder 2)
    physical description: half sheet folded; d. s.
    Commonwealth of Massachusetts. Resolution for payment of delegates to Continental Congress. Signed by Samuel Warren, Samuel Adams, and John Hancock. Docketed.
  - creator: Adams, John Quincy place: Peterborough, Jul 31, 1839; 055-004-A-2064; 4.0 pages (Box 13, Folder 3)
    physical description: wove paper, folded; a. l. s.
    To Gerrit Smith Predicts a civil war.
- Series V: Printed Materials
  Series V contains printed materials and Mr. Maass' notes relating to these items. The newspapers are divided by size into two groups, each of which is organized alphabetically by title.
  - Subseries A: Newspapers and Other Printed Materials
    Series V: Subseries A contains one legal box and two flat boxes of newspapers. Small-sized newspapers are arranged in alphabetical order in the legal box. A second alphabetical arrangement of larger-sized newspapers are housed in two flat boxes. Folders 55 through 62 contain manuscripts that were not assigned folder numbers during the original processing of the collection.
    - The Boston Chronicle vol. 1, no 54 place: Boston, Dec 26, 1768; 055-005-A-0787; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 1)
      physical description: full sheet in quarto; newspaper
      dimensions: 21cm x 27cm
    - The Boston Chronicle vol. 1, no. 48 place: Boston, Nov 14,1768; 055-005-A-0796; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - The Boston Chronicle vol. 1, no. 42 (2 copies) place: Boston, Oct 3, 1768; 055-005-A-0805; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - The Edinburgh Advertiser vol. 26, no. 1355 place: Edinburgh, Dec 24, 1776; 055-005-A-0814; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 2)
      dimensions: 22cm x 28cm
    - The Edinburgh Advertiser vol. 29, no. 1508 place: Edinburgh, Jun 12, 1778; 055-005-A-0823; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - The Glasgow Mercury vol. 3, no. 154 place: Glasgow, Dec 14, 1780; 055-005-A-1342; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 3)
      dimensions: 23cm x 31cm
    - The Glasgow Mercury vol.4, no. 196 place: Glasgow, Oct 4, 1781; 055-005-A-1351; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Lloyd's Evening Post vol. 48, no. 3713 place: London, Apr 9, 1781; 055-005-A-1360; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 3.5)
      dimensions: 22cm x 29cm
    - Lloyd's Evening Post vol. 29, no. 2201 place: London, Aug 12, 1771; 055-005-A-1369; 8.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 3.5)